Guide to the Agnese Nelms Haury Papers TAM.163
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Agnese Nelms Haury Papers
1925-2012
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Haury, A. N. (Agnese Nelms)
Lyons, Patrick D., 1969-
TAM.163
8 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes
9 videocassettes (vhs)
1 videocassettes (betamax)
2 audiocassettes
Agnese Nelms Haury (1923- ) a researcher, editor, author and philanthropist, has worked in and supported the work of others in a wide range of fields, including archaeology, anthropology, international affairs, Latin American studies, human rights, and the arts. She met Alger Hiss in the 1940s when he was president of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace and she was working in the Endowment's Publications Department. They became close associates and, from the time of Hiss's trials of the late 1940s and early 50s, she worked strenuously in the cause of his defense. The Haury Papers contain correspondence and subject files relating to the Agnese N. Lindley Foundation, the Community Foundation of Southern Arizona, The Nation Institute, and to research conducted by Tony Hiss, Bruce Craig, Jeff Kisseloff, John Lowenthal, and William A. Reuben on the Hiss defense and Hiss related research. The collection also documents the establishment of the Alger Hiss Archive, Alger Hiss Fellowship, and "The Alger Hiss Story" website. The collection also features audio visual sound and video recordings of interviews, television programs, and more pertaining to the Alger Hiss trial and Whittaker Chambers.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Agnese Nelms Haury in 2005. Haury donated a portion of her papers to the University of Arizona. In 2017 and 2018, the University of Arizona sent a donation of Haury's papers on Alger Hiss research to NYU; the accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2005.002, 2017.060 and 2018.133.
Arrangement
Folders arranged alphabetically by topic in both series.
The files are grouped into two series:
I. Alger Hiss Materials, 1948-2004
II. Subject Files, 1925-2004
Biographical Note
Agnese Haury (née Nelms) was born in Houston, Texas, in 1923. Educated in Fontainbleau, France; Houston, Texas; and Greenwich, Connecticut, she graduated from Bryn Mawr College in 1946 with a degree in history. She soon went to work in the Publications Department of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. While there she worked closely with Alger Hiss, who became president of the Endowment in 1947. At the Endowment she wrote and edited numerous reports and articles. She became assistant editor of International Conciliation (Carnegie Endowment) and associate editor of Intercom (Foreign Policy Association). From 1954 to 1959 she traveled to Bolivia, Peru, Ecuador, Libya, and Burma on special assignment for the Carnegie Endowment, making three surveys of technical assistance of the United Nations and its Specialized Agencies and of bilateral national programs. She was the author of Indians of the Andes (1956); Libya, Building a Desert Economy (1957); and The Burma Road to Pyidawtha (1958), all published by the Endowment.
Agnese Nelms married Manice deForest Lockwood 3rd in 1950. The two remained married until 1976. She was married to Denver Lindley from 1978 to 1982, and to Emil W. Haury from 1990 to 1992. After her years at the Carnegie Endowment, she held a variety of positions, including editor of several United Nations publications, editor of Anthropological Papers of the University of Arizona, and work on the Snaketown Archaeological Project.
The Agnese N. Lindley Foundation was established in the late 1970s to support projects in the fields of education, scientific advancement, the arts, human and civil rights, and the environment, as well as professional training related to these fields. She asked Alger Hiss to join the Board of Trustees of the Lindley Foundation when it was founded, and the two consulted closely on Foundation affairs for a number of years. She was a benefactor of the University of Arizona, where she established the Emil Haury Graduate Fellowship program in the Department of Anthropology, the Agnese Haury Institute for Court Interpretation, the A. N. Haury Fund for dendochronological studies, and the Haury Ceramic Heritage Fund at the Arizona State Museum. The University awarded her an honorary doctorate in 1999.
From the moment that Whittaker Chambers' accusations against Alger Hiss were first made public, Agnese Nelms became a researcher for and staunch supporter of Hiss's defense team. Her efforts on Hiss's behalf continued over the next half-century and more, and included the establishment in 1981 of the Alger Hiss Distinguished Professorship at Bard College, and assistance to the National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, The Nation Institute, and the National Security Archive.
Other Finding Aids
The microfilmed portion of this collection (Series I, Boxes 1 and 2) and the microfilmed portions of several other collections related to Alger Hiss at this repository form the microfilm edition of the Papers of Alger Hiss (comprised of Film R-7771B, R-7771C, R-7771D, and R-7771E). A published guide to the Papers of Alger Hiss microfilm edition is available at this repository (call number REF E743.5.H55 P38 2006).
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Related materials providing biographical information on Alger Hiss and information on the Hiss case can be found in the following collections in this repository (researchers must use microfilm where indicated):
John Lowenthal Papers (TAM 190) (Series 1, Boxes 1-5 on microfilm, Film R-7771C)
Alger Hiss Family Papers (TAM 314) (on microfilm, Film R-7771B: Series 1, Boxes 1-3; Series 2, Boxes 4-5; and Series 3, Box 6)
William A. Reuben Papers (TAM 289) (Series 1, Box 1 on microfilm, Film R-7771E)
A published guide to the microfilmed portions of these collections is available at this repository (call number REF E743.5.H55 P38 2006).
The Alger Hiss Defense Collection housed at the Harvard Law School Library, Harvard University consists of 115 boxes of materials amassed by Hiss's lawyers and additional materials related to Hiss's defense donated by Hiss researchers and supporters. The first three series of the Alger Hiss Defense Collection (Hiss Defense Files Series I, Hiss Defense Files Series II, and Hiss-Chambers Subject Files) are available at this repository on microfilm (Film R-7771A) and have an associated published guide (call number REF E743.5.H55 P37 2006). Materials excluded from the microfilm are available to researchers who use the collection on site at the Harvard Law School Library at Harvard University.
Scope and Contents
The Agnese Nelms Haury Papers include research materials into the Alger Hiss perjury trials and charitable foundations supported by Agnese Haury. Haury's files on Alger Hiss include personal correspondence with Hiss and his family, biographical information, and materials pertaining to the allegations against Hiss and the Hiss perjury trials. Materials related to the trials include Haury's handwritten notes, files on Bruce Craig's HUAC research, the Defense Fund for Alger Hiss, the "Pumpkin Papers," the Venona Papers and General Dmitri Volkogonov, the Woodstock typewriter, and the unsealing of 1948-49 Federal Grand Jury records. Among the correspondents represented are Alger and Tony Hiss, John Lowenthal, William A. Reuben, Allen Weinstein, and Bruce Craig. Files from Haury's charitable work include correspondence, notes, clippings, and background material related to the Agnese N. Lindley Foundation, the Community Foundation of Southern Arizona, The Nation Institute, the Alger Hiss archival collection at New York University, the Alger Hiss Fellowship, and "The Alger Hiss Story: Search for the Truth" website. The collection also contains clippings and research materials regarding President Richard Nixon, Sam Tanenhaus, Allen Weinstein, the Venona Cables, and issues concerning access to government documents.
Materials added to the collection in 2017 include additional Hiss research files and charitable donations in Hiss's name. They largely pertain to Haury's support of the Nation Institute's Alger Hiss Project, the Alger Hiss Endowed Chair at Bard College, and New York University's Center for the Cold War. These materials largely consist of organizing files related to these projects, but also include personal correspondence between Haury and Tony Hiss and John Lowenthal, both of whom were heavily involved in Hiss related research projects. Also included in these materials are copies of Hiss's petition for reinstatement to the Massachusetts Bar in 1975. In 2018, sound and video recordings were added to the collection, which consist of interviews, television programs, and more pertaining to the Alger Hiss trial and Whittaker Chambers.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Series I, Boxes 1 and 2 of the collection are available on microfilm (Film R-7771D) for use in this repository only. Researchers must use microfilm for this portion of the collection.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Custodial History
The Agnese Nelms Haury Papers was donated to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives by Agnese Nelms Haury in 2005. Haury donated a portion of her papers to the University of Arizona. In 2017, the University of Arizona sent a donation of Haury's papers on Alger Hiss research to NYU. In July 2018, the Arizona State Museum, University of Arizona sent a donation of 12 audio visual recordings relating to Alger Hiss and Whittaker Chambers. The accession number associated with these gifts are 2005.002, 2017.060, and 2018.133.
Articles.; Drafts (documents); Personal papers.; Trials (Perjury) -- United States.; Trials (Espionage) -- United States.; Cold War.; Anti-communist movements -- United States -- 20th century; Interviews.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.; Lockwood, Agnese Nelms; Hiss, Alger; Navasky, Victor S.; Rabinowitz, Victor; Volkogonov, Dmitri Antonovich.; Reuben, William A.; Smith, John Chabot; Weinstein, Allen; Lowenthal, John, 1925-2003; Hiss, Priscilla Fansler; Nation Institute (U.S.); Kisseloff, Jeff; Hiss, Tony; Agnese N. Lindley Foundation; Craig, R. Bruce.; Lyons, Patrick D., 1969-; Chambers, Whittaker
- Series I: Alger Hiss Materials, 1948-2004
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains original Hiss and Hiss family correspondence, biographical information on Alger Hiss and materials pertaining to the Hiss Case, including Haury's handwritten notes and files on Bruce Craig's HUAC research, the Defense Fund for Alger Hiss, the "Pumpkin Papers," the Venona Papers and Gen. Dmitri Volkogonov, the Woodstock typewriter, and the unsealing of 1948-49 Federal Grand Jury records. Among the correspondents represented are Alger and Tony Hiss, John Lowenthal, William A. Reuben, Allen Weinstein, and Bruce Craig. The series also contains materials pertaining to the Agnese M. Lindley Foundation, the Community Foundation of Southern Arizona, the Cold War International History Project, the National Emergency Civil Liberties Foundation, The Nation Institute, the National Security Archive, and the Public Citizen Litigation Group. Note: This series has been microfilmed as part of the Thomson-Gale Publishers collection, "Alger Hiss Papers at the Tamiment Library." Researchers should use the microfilm; consult archives staff for reel numbers.
  - Agnese N. Lindley Foundation, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Alger Hiss Story: Search for the Truth: Website, 1998-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aronson, James: WBAI Broadcast on Hiss, Feb 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bard College: Alger Hiss Endowed Chair, 1981-2002 (Box 5)
  - Blumenthal, Joe, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buttenweiser, Helen: Weinstein Case, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: James Shotwell, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1975-1976, 1981, 1984-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chervonnaya, Svetlana: Re: Vitaliy Pavlov, Mar 2001-Jun 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chervonnaya, Svetlana: Re: Vitaliy Pavlov, Aug 2002-Dec 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chervonnaya, Svetlana: Re: Vitaliy Pavlov, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chronology of FBI Relations with Henry Julian Wadleigh, Dec 15, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1950, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1984, 1986-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: Re: Hiss Case, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cold War International History Project and National Security Archive: Hiss Project, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Community Foundation of Southern Arizona: Correspondence, 2000, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Community Foundation of Southern Arizona, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Cook, Fred, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Corry, Katherine, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cowles, Russell, Sep 13, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Craig, Bruce: "Ales"/Pierce Research, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Craig, Bruce: Baltimore Documents re: Hiss, Microscopy, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Craig, Bruce: Chambers-Trotsky Connection, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Craig, Bruce: Craig v. USA, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Craig, Bruce: HUAC Research re: Hiss, 1999-2002 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cross, Claude: Chief Counsel for Hiss's Second Trial, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Day, Anthony: Los Angeles Times, Editor, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Defense Fund for Alger Hiss, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Defense Fund for Alger Hiss: Contributors, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Defense Fund for Alger Hiss: Contributors, 1950, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Defense Fund for Alger Hiss: Richard Field, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Draper, Theodore: Review Articles on Hiss Case (New York Review of Books), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Eddy, George: Correspondence re: Manuscript, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Eddy, George: Draft of Manuscript (Agnese Nelms Haury copy), 1997 (Box 8)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee: Alger Hiss Case, Fundraising, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Field, Richard, undated, 1950, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1978, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Request re: Alger Hiss, 1976, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - FOIA Requests re: Whittaker Chambers, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Goodyear, Steve: Harvard Law Record Material, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Halsey, Margaret, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Harvard Law Library, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Hinson, Kathryn, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Hiss, Alger: Apartment and Care, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Hiss, Alger: Articles by, 1973, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hiss, Alger: Biographical Information, 1973, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Hiss, Alger: Correspondence, 1958, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Hiss, Alger: Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hiss, Alger: Correspondence, 1980-1984, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hiss, Alger: Estate of, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hiss, Alger: Funeral, Nov 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hiss, Alger: Interviews, 1974, 1978, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hiss, Alger: Letters of Support to Hiss (Copies), Aug 1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hiss, Alger: Letters to the Editor, 1984, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hiss, Alger: Obituaries, Nov 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hiss, Alger: Recollections of a Life (Comments, etc.), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hiss, Alger: Schedule, 1976, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger: "Yalta," Pocket Book Magazine, Sep 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Anna, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: Hand-written Notes, 1973, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: "Pumpkin Papers", 1975, 1986, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: Theater and Television, Mar 1984-Oct 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: Typewriter, 1952, 1958, 1962-1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: Unsealing Federal Grand Jury Records, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: Unsealing Federal Grand Jury Records, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hiss, Donald, 1972-1974, 1989, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hiss, Isabel Johnson, 1967, 1970s, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hiss, Mary, 1950, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hiss, Priscilla, 1978, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hiss, Tony: Alger Hiss Research and Education Project, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Hiss, Tony: Articles re: Tony Hiss, undated, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hiss, Tony: Correspondence, 1971, 1976, 1982- 2003 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hiss, Tony: Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 7)
  - Hiss, Tony: "I Call on Alger," Interview with Alger Hiss (Rolling Stone), Sep 13, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Hobson, Timothy, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Horwitz, Sari, Jan 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Kisseloff, Jeff: "The Hiss Case Revisited", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Kisseloff, Jeff: "New Debate on the Hiss Case", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Krieger, Sam, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Kursh, Harry, Jun 1961-Sep 1961 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Langer, Elinor: "Witness" (Grand Street, Vol. 3 No. 4), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Levin, David, 1975-1976, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lowenthal, John, 1975-1976, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lowenthal, John: Correspondence, 1983-2003 (Box 5)
  - Lowenthal, John: Hiss Film Project, Jul 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lowenthal, John: "The Trials of Alger Hiss", 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Marbury, William: Obituary (New York Times), Mar 7, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Marks, Jack A.: Tape Transcript, Jul 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - McLean, Edward, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Metzger, Lois, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Moore, William, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Murphy, Franklin: Los Angeles Times, Chairman, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Nation Institute: Press Conference re: Alger Hiss, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Nation Institute: "Press Reactions to the Nation Institute's Cold War Archive Project", 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Nation Institute: The Alger Hiss Project, 1998-2012 (Box 6, Box 7)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Foundation: Re: Alger Hiss, 1975-1980, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Navasky, Victor S., 1973, 1978, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - New York University: Alger Hiss Collection, 2006-2008 (Box 5)
  - New York University: Hiss Archival Collection and Center for the United States and the Cold War, 2002-2007 (Box 7)
  - Nixon, Richard: Testimony re: Alger Hiss, Nov 13, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Popkin, Richard, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Public Citizen Litigation Group: Alger Hiss Case, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Public Citizen Litigation Group: Press Conference re: Alger Hiss Grand Jury Records, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Public Citizen Litigation Group: Request for Alger Hiss Grand Jury Records, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Request, etc., 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA Request, etc., 1998 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: FOIA Request, etc., 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Recordings of Interviews and Television Programs, 1978-2002 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    The box contains 9 VHS tapes, 1 Video Cassette (BETA), and 2 audio cassette tapes.
  - Reinstatement to Massachusetts Bar, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Salant, Stephen: "First Crisis, First 'Tapes': Did Nixon Obstruct Justice in the Hiss Case?", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Shepherd, Peter, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Smith, John Chabot, 1974-1979, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Tiger, Edith: In Re: Alger Hiss (Agnese Haury copy, signed by Tiger and Alger Hiss), 1978 (Box 8)
  - Transcripts of Road to Middle East Peace Conference, 1989 (Box 6, Box 7)
  - Volkogonov, Dmitri, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Weinstein, Allen, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Perjury, 1978, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Whitman, Alden: New York Times, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Zeligs, Meyer, 1960, 1967, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1925-2003.
  This series contains correspondence, notes, clippings, and background material related to the Agnese N. Lindley Foundation, the Community Foundation of Southern Arizona, The Nation Institute, and other topics. Some files relate to research conducted by Tony Hiss, Bruce Craig, Jeff Kisseloff, John Lowenthal, and William A. Reuben on the Hiss Case; other materials document the establishment of the Alger Hiss Archive, the Alger Hiss Fellowship and "The Alger Hiss Story: Search for the Truth" website. The collection also contains clippings and research materials regarding President Richard Nixon, Sam Tanenhaus, Allen Weinstein, the Venona Cables, and issues concerning access to government documents.
  - Agnese N. Lindley Foundation, 1986, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alger Hiss Archive, undated, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alger Hiss Fellowship, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Alger Hiss Story: Website, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Blumenthal, Joe, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brower, Brock: "Spying's Dirty Little Secret," Money, Jul 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Buttenweiser, Helen: Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cameron, Agnes: Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Challener, Richard: "New Light on a Turning Point in U.S. History," University, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clayton, W.L.: Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate: "Scope of Soviet Activity in the United States, Part 66", 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Community Foundation of Southern Arizona (CFSA): Alger Hiss Research and Educational Program, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CFSA: Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CFSA: Financial Data, 1998-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CFSA: Funding, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CFSA: Christopher Richards/Hiss Research, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - CFSA: Jeannie McCloskey/Hiss Research, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cook, Fred: Articles in The Nation re: Hiss, Sep 1957-Oct 1957 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1950, 1956-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Craig, Bruce: Correspondence, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Craig, Bruce: Chambers-Trotsky Connection, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Craig, Bruce: "The Hiss-Chambers Controversy: Records of the HUAC", 2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Craig, Bruce: Nixon Tapes Re: Hiss, 1999, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Craig, Bruce: "Trip Report: Edward R. Stettinius Papers, University of Virginia", 2001 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Danenberg, Leigh: Correspondence, Jun 10, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 26)